IAN MUNENE

TECHNICAL PRODUCT MANAGER

AWARDS

Pesapal Hackathon Runner's Up

October

PesaPal

LANGUAGES

English C1

Swahili

Native

HOBBIES

Hockey

Reading Novels

Running

OBJECTIVE

Having worked in technology for the past five years in various roles, I've developed a passion for creating products as a software engineer as well as defining roadmaps and deciding what product features carry the most weight for customers. I've worked as part of distributed teams and believe my strongest skills to be in project management as well as overseeing all facets of product design that include; planning, resource allocation, testing, and implementation. Gathering feedback on product has also been essential in my various roles to make certain of market alignment and product fit.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Talent-Bridge Africa

Software Engineer (Backend)

(October 2020 - Present)

As an engineer, my work involves building user-facing features as well as designing the product roadmap in collaboration with the product manager in preparation for a January launch of the platform. Working with the Rails framework and React in the frontend.

Generation

Curriculum Consultant

(January 2020 - August 2020)

In this role, I worked with the Generation Brazil team to create a new curriculum for the pioneer Generation Coding Bootcamp we were starting to train junior software engineers in France and the U.K. I created modules of Java-Spring curriculum that contained integrated team and professional skills that would help job seekers get their first jobs. They are currently running their pilot class.

Andela

Curriculum Manager

(June 2018 - February 2020)

My role involved learning the needs of the developer ecosystem at Andela and providing the right resources to help engineers on their partner engagements. This was one of the initiatives that led to the reduction of developer attrition from 8% to 5.5%.

Loyalty Club

Product Manager

(January 2017 - Present)

As a Product Manager, I worked with the team to define the company roadmap, ran beta, and pilot programs with early-stage product features. I also conducted market research on future product features by making visits to customers and non-customers.

Moringa School

Curriculum and Learning Experience Lead

(August 2017 - May 2018)

My role involved creating software development learning paths for aspiring developers using the blended learning model of instruction. These paths have gone on to be used by thousands of aspiring developers to get their first job. At the time of leaving, Moringa School had a hiring rate above 75%.

Accelerate Bootcamps HongKong

Classroom Lead

(January 2017 - June 2017)

In this role, I led the classroom team in delivering a high-quality experience using the blended learning model. We (the classroom team) also put in place operational systems necessary for the smooth running of the classroom. The hiring rate for the class was above 60%.

Moringa School

Software Development Instructor

(January 2016 - January 2017)

In this role, I taught software development technologies to aspiring software developers. During this time, we made a successful transition from a traditional model of instruction to the blended learning model. At my time of departure, the hiring rate of developers was above 90%.

Moringa School

Software Developer

(April 2015 - April 2016)

In this role, I was primarily involved in the building of useful companion tools for students learning software development. One of these tools was a self-check-in system that students used to mark attendance. I also configured a lightweight opensource CMS that was used to host content for the School.

EDUCATION

Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology

Bachelors Degree Bsc Computer Technology

(May 2010 - December 2014)

Kiambu High School

High School Diploma High School

(February 2006 - November 2009)

SKILLS

Product Management Intermediate

Curriculum Design

Advanced

Advanced

Advanced

Communication

Giving Feedback

Advanced

Problem Solving Intermediate

Receiving Feedback Advanced **Project Management**

Learning Experience Design

Advanced

REFERENCES

Savannah Kunovsky Former CTO Moringa School sekunovsky@gmail.com

Nora Studholme

Director of Strategy Andela nora.studholme@andela.com

Jyoti Gupta

Former Director of Curriculum Andela jgupta71@hotmail.com